<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tracing with X-Ray on Amazon Chatbot Workshop</title>
    <link>/x-ray/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tracing with X-Ray on Amazon Chatbot Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>

	<atom:link href="/x-ray/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />


    <item>
      <title>Modify IAM Role</title>
      <link>/x-ray/role/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/x-ray/role/</guid>
      <description>In order for the X-Ray daemon to communicate with the service, we need to add a policy to the worker nodes&amp;rsquo; AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) role.
First, we will need to ensure the Role Name our workers use is set in our environment:
test -n &amp;quot;$ROLE_NAME&amp;quot; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; echo ROLE_NAME is &amp;quot;$ROLE_NAME&amp;quot; || echo ROLE_NAME is not set    Expand here if you need to export the Role Name   If ROLE_NAME is not set, please review: /eksctl/test/</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Deploy X-Ray DaemonSet</title>
      <link>/x-ray/x-ray-daemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/x-ray/x-ray-daemon/</guid>
      <description>Now that we have modified the IAM role for the worker nodes to permit write operations to the X-Ray service, we are going to deploy the X-Ray DaemonSet to the EKS cluster. The X-Ray daemon will be deployed to each worker node in the EKS cluster. For reference, see the example implementation used in this module.
The AWS X-Ray SDKs are used to instrument your microservices. When using the DaemonSet in the example implementation, you need to configure it to point to xray-service.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Deploy Example Microservices</title>
      <link>/x-ray/microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/x-ray/microservices/</guid>
      <description>We now have the foundation in place to deploy microservices, which are instrumented with X-Ray SDKs, to the EKS cluster.
In this step, we are going to deploy example front-end and back-end microservices to the cluster. The example services are already instrumented using the X-Ray SDK for Go. Currently, X-Ray has SDKs for Go, Python, Node.js, Ruby, .NET and Java.
kubectl apply -f https://eksworkshop.com/x-ray/sample-front.files/x-ray-sample-front-k8s.yml kubectl apply -f https://eksworkshop.com/x-ray/sample-back.files/x-ray-sample-back-k8s.yml  To review the status of the deployments, you can run:</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>X-Ray Console</title>
      <link>/x-ray/x-ray/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/x-ray/x-ray/</guid>
      <description>We now have the example microservices deployed, so we are going to investigate our Service Graph and Traces in X-Ray section of the AWS Management Console.
The Service map in the console provides a visual representation of the steps identified by X-Ray for a particular trace. Each resource that sends data to X-Ray within the same context appears as a service in the graph. In the example below, we can see that the x-ray-sample-front-k8s service is processing 39 transactions per minute with an average latency of 0.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Cleanup</title>
      <link>/x-ray/cleanup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/x-ray/cleanup/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations on completing the Tracing with X-Ray module.
The content for this module was based on the Application Tracing on Kubernetes with AWS X-Ray blog post.
This module is not used in subsequent steps, so you can remove the resources now or at the end of the workshop.
Delete the Kubernetes example microservices deployed:
kubectl delete deployments x-ray-sample-front-k8s x-ray-sample-back-k8s kubectl delete services x-ray-sample-front-k8s x-ray-sample-back-k8s  Delete the X-Ray DaemonSet:
kubectl delete -f https://eksworkshop.</description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
