<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GitOps with Weave Flux on Amazon Chatbot Workshop</title>
    <link>/weave_flux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GitOps with Weave Flux on Amazon Chatbot Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 19:56:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>

	<atom:link href="/weave_flux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />


    <item>
      <title>Prereqs</title>
      <link>/weave_flux/prereqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 19:56:14 -0400</pubDate>

      <guid>/weave_flux/prereqs/</guid>
      <description>Is helm installed? We will use helm to install Weave Flux and a sample Helm chart. Check to see if helm is installed:
helm version  If helm is not found, see installing helm for instructions.

Does S3 artifact bucket exist and are IAM service roles created? AWS CodePipeline and AWS CodeBuild both need AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) service roles to create a Docker image build pipeline.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>GitHub Setup</title>
      <link>/weave_flux/githubsetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/weave_flux/githubsetup/</guid>
      <description>We are going to create 2 GitHub repositories. One will be used for a sample application that will trigger a Docker image build. Another will be used to hold Kubernetes manifests that Weave Flux deploys into the cluster. Note this is a pull based method compared to other continuous deployment tools that push to Kubernetes.
Create the sample application repository by clicking here.
Fill in the form with repository name, description, and check initializing the repository with a README as shown below and click Create repository.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Install Weave Flux</title>
      <link>/weave_flux/installweaveflux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/weave_flux/installweaveflux/</guid>
      <description>Now we will use Helm to install Weave Flux into our cluster and enable it to interact with our Kubernetes configuration GitHub repo.
First, install the Flux Custom Resource Definition:
kubectl apply -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fluxcd/flux/helm-0.10.1/deploy-helm/flux-helm-release-crd.yaml  Check that Tiller is installed.
helm ls  When tiller has already been installed, this command should either return a list of helm charts that have already been deployed or nothing.
If you get the message Error: could not find tiller, see installing helm for instructions.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Create Image with CodePipeline</title>
      <link>/weave_flux/codepipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/weave_flux/codepipeline/</guid>
      <description>Now we are going to create the AWS CodePipeline using AWS CloudFormation. This pipeline will be used to build a Docker image from your GitHub source repo (eks-example). Note that this does not deploy the image. Weave Flux will handle that.
CloudFormation is an infrastructure as code (IaC) tool which provides a common language for you to describe and provision all the infrastructure resources in your cloud environment. CloudFormation allows you to use a simple text file to model and provision, in an automated and secure manner, all the resources needed for your applications across all regions and accounts.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Deploy from Manifests</title>
      <link>/weave_flux/deploymentmanifests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/weave_flux/deploymentmanifests/</guid>
      <description>Now we are ready to use Weave Flux to deploy the hello world application into our Amazon EKS cluster. To do this we will clone our GitHub config repository (k8s-config) and then commit Kubernetes manifests to deploy.
Update the username (YOURUSER) below to match your GitHub user name.
 cd .. git clone https://github.com/YOURUSER/k8s-config.git cd k8s-config mkdir charts namespaces releases workloads  Create a namespace Kubernetes manifest.
cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF &amp;gt; namespaces/eks-example.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Deploy from Helm</title>
      <link>/weave_flux/deploymenthelm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/weave_flux/deploymenthelm/</guid>
      <description>You can use this same approach to deploy Helm charts. These charts can exist within the configuration Git repository (k8s-config), or hosted from an external chart repository. In this example we will use an external chart to keep things simple.
In your k8s-config directory, create a namespace manifest.
The git pull command ensures we have the latest configuration in case Flux modified anything.
 cd ../k8s-config git pull cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF &amp;gt; namespaces/nginx.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Cleanup</title>
      <link>/weave_flux/cleanup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/weave_flux/cleanup/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations on completing the GitOps with Weave Flux module.
This module is not used in subsequent steps, so you can remove the resources now, or at the end of the workshop.
First, delete all images from the Amazon ECR Repository.
Next, go to the CloudFormation Console and delete the stack used to deploy the image build CodePipeline
Now, delete Weave Flux and your load balanced services
helm delete flux --purge kubectl delete ns flux kubectl delete crd helmreleases.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/weave_flux/app.files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>/weave_flux/app.files/</guid>
      <description> Hello World  Hello World! Server&amp;nbsp;address: server_address
Server&amp;nbsp;name: server_hostname
Date: server_date
URI: server_url
 </description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
